# **ROB WILLIFORD**

336-456-5834

@ self.rswillif@gmail.com

rswillif.github.io

Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina Area

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Software Engineer

Freelance

math display="block" of the control of the control

**♀** Raleigh, NC

Various

 Freelance, full-stack software development consulting on various client projects. Industries include freight supply chain, entertainment, healthcare, and energy industries. Majority of projects utilize AWS, OpenJDK 8/11, ReactJS, and NodeJS. Work sourced through Vaco LLC and Eliassen Group

### Software Engineer

PrecisionHawk

**11/2019 - 09/2020** 

**♀** Raleigh, NC

Drone/Software Solutions for Energy and Agriculture

 (Full-time) Full-stack react and java8/openjdk development on AWS infrastructure for an application that allows energy companies to monitor the transmission lines and components of their electrical grid infrastructure.

### Software Engineer

**IBM** 

**1** 03/2019 - 10/2019

**♀** RTP

Cloud, IT, and IoT solutions

 (Full-time) Built automated solutions using Python for database data migrations for quote to cash financial information. Worked on distributed cloud-native application with a distributed systems back-end implemented in Go, ReactJS front-ends, and using Kubernetes. Focusing on optimizing datastreaming capabilities for file upload/download, and gathering and aggregating associated financial metadata. (CIO department).

### Software Engineer

Cisco

**1** 06/2017 - 03/2019

**♀** RTP

Digital Security and Networking Solutions

• (Contract) Full-stack web development. (Web application that assesses the viability of software images to be deployed to production systems by analyzing file contents). Led the development on service integrations and page navigation mechanisms, and expanded the functionality of numerous back-end services. Deployed on a hybrid-cloud infrastructure. Used: heavy Ruby and JS usage as well as some Go, Java, and Python.

### **Back-End Developer**

iCiDigital

**#** 02/2017 - 06/2017

Raleigh, NC

Software Consultancy

#### Junior Web Developer

The Iron Yard

**1** 09/2016 - 12/2016

Ourham, NC

Web Development Bootcamp

### Data Analyst

Stealz, Inc.

**1** 05/2016 - 08/2016

**♀** Raleigh, NC

Mobile Internet Marketing Application

### **Graduate Research Assistant**

North Carolina State University

**1** 05/2015 - 08/2015

Raleigh, NC

Machine Learning Lab

### **EDUCATION**

### B.S. Environmental Science/Mathematics

North Carolina State University

**1** 08/2011 - 05/2016

**♀** Raleigh, NC

### **SUMMARY**

I have over 4 years of industry experience, and I like pushing the boundaries of what people think is possible. I enjoy working on applications that have the potential to shift paradigms, and value and like to help cultivate empathy and collaboration in a team oriented environment.

#### **SKILLS**

### Languages

Java Javascript

Ruby

Python

Go

#### Frameworks

Ruby on Rails

NodeJS

Buffalo

ReactJS

Flask

Spring

#### Cloud

AWS

IBM Cloud

Pivotal

### Infrastructure

PostgreSQL

Redis

Heroku | Git

Jira

Apache Sling

MariaDB

CassandraDB

Linux

ux Kubernetes

CloudFoundry

nginx

**AWS Batch** 

ElasticSearch
Cloud Functions

AWS ECS

Docker

MariaDB

AWS S3

AWS Serverless

Terraform Jenkins

## PASSIONS

<

Open Source

**®** 

Physics/Mathematics

×

**Traveling** 

**/** 

Environment